Mathura Govindarajan

Contact Number: +91-9945835041 | Email: mmg9291@gmail.com | Web-page: www.mathuramg.com

SUMMARY

Equipped with work experience as a technical analyst in Goldman Sachs and skilled in data analysis and software development. Re-engineered and developed intuitive front end tools used for sales analytics in accelerated timelines. Highly accomplished in multiple forms of fine arts and led design groups in stage productions and video animations.

EXPERIENCE

Goldman Sachs Pvt. Ltd. - Bangalore, India

June 2013 - Current

Technical Analyst, Private Wealth Management

- Member of Management Information Systems (MIS) team in the Private Wealth Management business.
- Responsible for developing front end tools and delivering data to the sales and management teams.
- Instrumental in the re-engineering of data analytics tool which assisted in increased productivity of the sales force and management.

National Institute of Technology Karnataka – Surathkal (NITK), Mangalore, India

Aug 2012 – Apr 2013

Final Year Project, Digital Signal Processing Laboratory

- Researched on methods to enable the early detection of Alzheimer's disease using MRI scans.
- Developed image processing algorithms prototyped in MATLAB® and implemented in OpenCV.

Goldman Sachs Pvt. Ltd. - Bangalore, India

May 2012 – July 2012

Summer Intern, Private Wealth Management

- Member of team responsible for managing sales data that flows into the Private Wealth Management business.
- Implemented increased data storage capacities using cloud storage and developed a secure web portal that increased the ease of access and distribution of data.

School of Business and Engineering, Vaud (HEIG-VD) Switzerland

June 2011 - July 2011

Exchange Student, Digital Signal Processing Laboratory

- Studied the real time applications of signal processing in partnership with students from NITK and HEIG-VD.
- Developed and implemented image, sound and video algorithms that facilitated fast and accurate results in MATLAB® and Code Composer Studio v4.

Indian Institute of Science – Bangalore, India

May 2011 – June 2011

Summer Intern, Supercomputer Education and Research Centre (SERC)

- Analyzed the requirement of the cache memory in streaming and non-streaming applications on a smart phone.
- Benchmarked various standard and non-standard cache performance using Pin tool and developed cache simulation in C.

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATION

National Institute of Technology Karnataka

May 2009 - May 2013

B. Tech, Electronics and Computer Engineering

- Rank 4 out of 107 students with a CGPA of 9.36/10 at the end of the course.
- Rank 1 out of 107 students in 2010 and was awarded the Certificate of Merit for Excellence in Academics.
- **Presented a paper** on Utility of Image Processing on MRI Scan for Early detection of Alzheimer's Disease in the 3rd International Symposium (IES 2013) in Kumamoto University, Japan
- One of the 3 students selected out of 107 to attend the Summer University Program on signal processing in School
 of Business and Engineering, HEIG-VD, Switzerland.
- Runner-up in the **OPJEMS Scholarship Exam in 2009** based on scholastic and non-scholastic performance.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming Languages: JavaScript, HTML5, SQL, Perl, C, C++, Java, Assembly programming for ARM7
- Technical Suites/Packages: MATLAB®, Simulink, PSpice, Pin Tool, Xilinx, Inkscape, QlikView, Aqua Data Studio, Eclipse IDE, Keil uVision, MS Office
- Platforms: Windows and UNIX (Linux and Macintosh)

PROJECTS

Technical Projects

- Designed and implemented a perpetual motion system around a mechanical geared clock which was on display during Engineer-2012 (Technical fest of NITK Surathkal, one of the largest in South India, www.nitk.ac.in/students-activities/engineer)
- Engineered a 24x16 LED screen spanning 2 floors of a building and programmed classic video games that could be played from half a kilometer away during *Engineer-2011*.

Design Projects

- Co-headed the stage and publicity design team for a theatre production supporting a children's education charity.
- Designed logo for the production unit of Seva-in-Action, an NGO operating out of Bangalore, Karnataka which focuses on the rehabilitation of persons with disabilities.

Video Animations

www.youtube.com/user/mmg9291/videos

- Directed shadow puppet trailer for a theatre production supporting a children's education charity
- Conceptualized and produced Claymation video for publicity of Engineer, 2012

 Technical fest of National Institute of Technology Karnataka, India.
- Part of 6 member team that created flipbook animation video for Engineer, 2011

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

- Placement Coordinator Key member in recruiting organizations and procuring job opportunities at NITK Surathkal.
- Chairperson of the Computer Society of India (CSI NITK CHAPTER) Responsible for co-heading 90 students and conducting various technical events through the college.
- Secured fourth place in E-Pitch, the B-Plan event held at Engineer 2010, a national level technical symposium organized by NITK, Surathkal.
- Placed in the top 50 teams in Asia in the B-plan competition Euphoria conducted by IIT-Bombay.
- **Head of creative committee** in *Incident, 2013* (Cultural fest of NITK Surathkal, one of the largest in South India www.nitk.ac.in/students-activities/incident)
- Executive Member of the Artists' Forum in NITK Surathkal contributed towards many Art Exhibitions and Expos.